vetsfirstchoice.com 2015-04-13

# VETS FIRST CHOICE PET OWNER SERVICES PRIVACY POLICY

VETS FIRST CHOICE
PET OWNER SERVICES PRIVACY POLICY
PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE.
Last Updated: January 01, 2015
Direct Vet Marketing, Inc. (hereinafter, “Vets First Choice,” “we,” “us”, “our”) provides this web site located at
www.vetsfirstchoice.com, our mobile applications and all content and services available through our web site and our
mobile applications (collectively, the “Site”) subject to this Privacy Policy along with the Terms of Service for
Participating Veterinary Practices (the “Terms of Service”).
BY ACCESSING AND/OR BY USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE
SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION AND NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS
PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF SERVICE, AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. If you do not agree
with these terms, you do not have permission to use the Site or to provide any Personal Information to us.
1. General.
We do not collect any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) unless you voluntarily provide it to
us. While you may use some of the functionality of the Site without registration, some of the features and services
available through the Site might require you to create an account. If you do not create an account on the Site, the
only information we collect from you will be “Non-Personal Information” (i.e., Information that cannot be used to
identify you, including information such as the web pages that you have viewed), as more fully described below. If
you choose create an account through the Site, we may require you to submit Personal Information. You are
responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the Personal Information you submit to Vets First Choice. Inaccurate or out
of data information will affect the information you receive when using the Site and our ability to contact you.
2. The Information We Gather
Vets First Choice gathers two types of information about users:
          2.1. Non-Personal Information. We may collect and aggregate certain Non-Personal Information from the
users of our Site, including, without limitation, data regarding, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which
the pages of the Site were visited, and the hyperlinks which were “clicked.” Collecting such information involves the
logging of the IP addresses, operating system, and browser software used by each Site user. Although such
information is not Personal Information, we can determine from an IP address a user’s Internet Service Provider and
the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.
Cookies allow Vets First Choice to serve you better and more efficiently, personalize your experience with the Site
and services offered on the Site, determine the length of time each user spends at any particular area of the Site, and
ascertain the specific functionality that users choose to use. Cookies also may be used to facilitate a user’s log-in, but
are not used to retain any Personal Information. Most browsers allow you to control how and whether Cookies will be
accepted. If you reject our Cookies, certain of the functions and conveniences of the Site may not work properly, but
you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to use portions of the Site.
          2.2. Personal Information. We collect Personal Information from users at several different points on this
Site, including, without limitation, when you create an account, make purchases in our online store, provide
information to the veterinarians and veterinary practices that participate in our Site, utilize social media and live chat,
subscribe to e-mail newsletters, send e-cards or e-mails, participate in contests, sweepstakes and other promotions,
or participate in online polls and surveys.
     (a) Creating an Account. In order to make purchases or access the medicine cabinet in our online store, we
          will require you to create an account with us. During this process, you will need to provide us with Personal
          Information as well as information about your pet and the veterinarian who cares for your pet. You
          acknowledge and agree that you are required to provide accurate and current information when registering
          for an account on our Site.
     (b) Making Purchases. When purchasing products or services through the Site, users are required to provide
          Vets First Choice with Personal Information as specified on the Site at the time of purchase. Vets First
          Choice uses this Personal Information to process the order, send the product and/or provide the service. If
          the purchase is a gift, we may also collect information about the recipient, such as name and mailing
          address.

    (c) Exchanges of Information With the Veterinary Practices That Are Our Customers. You may be asked
         to provide certain Personal Information to our customers (e.g. your veterinarian or veterinary practice that
         participate in our Site) when you order products through this Site. Vets First Choice is not responsible for the
         privacy practices of our customers. If you choose to provide Personal Information to one of our customers,
         be aware that the such customer’s privacy policy (and not this policy) will apply to the Personal Information
         and other information that you elect to share with the customer. Accordingly, you are advised review the
         particular customer’s privacy policy before sharing any information with the customer. The veterinary
         practices that participate on our Site may upload to the Site contact information (which may include your
         Personal Information) they have collected through other means, such as Personal Information collected from
         you when you bring in your pet for an office visit.
    (d) Subscribing to Newsletters. You may subscribe to e-mail newsletters offered by us. When you subscribe
         to our e-mail newsletter(s), we may ask for your first and last name, e-mail address, age and gender.
    (e) Participating In Contests, Sweepstakes and Other Promotions. From time to time, Vets First Choice
         may offer you the opportunity to participate in a contest, sweepstakes, rewards program or other promotion
         through the Site (each, a “Promotion”). If you elect to participate in any such Promotion, you will be asked to
         provide us with certain information necessary to conduct such Promotion, and your participation will be
         subject to the Terms of Use for this Site and any other rules applicable to such Promotion and posted on the
         Site.
    (f)  Participating in Online Polls and Surveys. Vets First Choice may, from time to time, utilize online polls
         and/or surveys. If you elect to participate in any such online poll or survey, you may be asked to provide us
         with Personal Information, or you may be asked to provide only information that is not personally identifiable
         (such as first name only, city or state of residence, age, gender, or dog breed owned).
3. Use of the Information We Gather
Vets First Choice uses the Personal Information and Non-Personal Information that is collected via the Site for the
purposes set forth below:
         3.1. Non-Personal Information. Vets First Choice uses Non-Personal Information primarily in aggregate
form to build higher quality, more useful services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics
and behavior of our users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Site.
         3.2. Personal Information.
    (a) Account Creation. Vets First Choice may use the Personal Information that we collect from you when you
         create an account to contact you in connection with your use of the Site and to track who uses the various
         features and functionality offered at the Site. Additionally, we may use this information in determining the
         types of features, functionality, products and services to offer through the Site or otherwise.
    (b) Purchases. Vets First Choice uses the Personal Information collected during the purchasing process to
         fulfill the order, send the product and/or provide the service.
    (c) Newsletter Subscriptions. Vets First Choice uses contact information collected during subscription to send
         you the newsletter.
    (d) E-Mails. When you provide Personal Information to send an e-mail using the Site, Vets First Choice will only
         use the information given to send the e-mail and will not retain the information once the e-mail is sent. In any
         event, anyone receiving emails from Vets First Choice on behalf of our customers always has the
         opportunity to opt-out of email messages via the opt-out link included in the footer of the message.
    (e) Promotions. Vets First Choice uses the Personal Information, if any, it may collect from you related to a
         contest, sweepstakes or other promotion (each, a “Promotion”) through the Site for administering the
         Promotion. This Personal Information will not be re-used, sold or shared in any manner by Vets First Choice
         or any third parties unless you elect to receive additional information and promotional material from Vets
         First Choice and/or third parties. If a third party administers the Promotion, your participation may be subject
         to that third party's terms and conditions, and privacy policy. Detailed information about these terms will be
         provided on the applicable form you will be asked to fill out in order to participate in the Promotion.
                                                              2

     (f)  Communications with Vets First Choice. When you send an e-mail message to or otherwise contact Vets
          First Choice, Vets First Choice may (i) use the information provided by you to respond to your
          communication and/or as described in this Privacy Policy; and (ii) archive this information.
4. Sharing and Disclosing Personal Information. Vets First Choice does not sell your Personal Information and
Non-Personal Information. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are
certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Information and/or Non-Personal Information with certain
third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below:
     (a) Aggregate Data. Vets First Choice may share aggregate data about our users with our partners, such as
          data gathered from online polls or surveys.
     (b) Disclosure for Operations and Maintenance. Vets First Choice consultants and contractors
          (“Consultants”) sometimes have limited access to your Personal Information in the course of providing
          products or services to Vets First Choice. These Consultants include vendors and suppliers that provide us
          with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of the Site. Unless
          you have opted-out of receiving e-mails and newsletters from Vets First Choice, these Consultants also may
          have access to your e-mail address to send newsletters to you on our behalf. Access to your Personal
          Information by these Consultants is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the Consultants to
          perform its limited function for Vets First Choice. We also contractually require that our Consultants not use
          or disclose your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services,
          and that the Consultants secure your Personal Information with safeguards equivalent to our own
          safeguards.
     (c) Government Authorities; Legal Rights and Actions. Vets First Choice may share your Personal
          Information with various government authorities in response to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal
          process; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by
          law. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also
          may share your Personal Information when we believe it is appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action
          regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities; to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of the
          Site, our users, customers, or others; and in connection with our Terms of Service and other applicable
          agreements. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personal Information to a third party,
          we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate law or a court order. Vets First Choice reserves
          the right to report any suspected illegal activity to, and cooperate with, law enforcement individuals or
          entities for investigation or prosecution.
     (d) Exchanges of Information With the Veterinary Practices That Are Our Customers. Vets First Choice
          may share your Personal Information with the veterinarians and veterinary practices that provide care for
          your pet.
     (e) Business Transfers: As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event
          of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Information may be part of
          the transferred assets.
5. Cookies and Web Beacons
Vets First Choice uses a variety of technologies on our sites. Among these are cookies: a text-only string of
information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website
can remember your browser in the future. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the
cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a unique number. When you visit our Site, open
our email, or encounter our services online (perhaps on a customer's website) we may send you a cookie. Cookies
may be used in many ways: they allow us to verify the login status of customers using products or services linked
directly with our website, track point of entry to point of registration for those users participating in our affiliate signup
programs, and track and measure the success of a particular marketing campaign. Cookies also allow us to track
overall site usage and determine areas users prefer, enabling us to make your visit to our website easier by
recognizing you when you return and helping to provide you with a customized experience.
Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any Personal Information while on our Site. You have the ability to accept or
decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. If you choose to disable cookies, you may still use our Site;
however, you may have limited access to some areas within our Site. For more information on how to manage
cookies in your web browser, see http://www.aboutcookies.org. We also provide you with an option to opt-out of
receiving certain cookies associated with our online advertising. See "Online Advertising" below.
                                                                3

Some of our web pages, emails, and other online content may contain electronic images known as web beacons,
also known as single-pixel GIFs, which are invisible graphical images. These web beacons allow us to count users
who have visited our web pages, seen our ads, or opened our email. Web beacons collect only limited information,
such as a cookie identifier, time and date of a page being viewed, and a description of the page on which the Web
Beacon resides (the URL).
Flash cookies are also created by certain content on our pages using Adobe® Flash®, such as product tutorials.
Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie
management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and
storage settings for Flash cookies see,
http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html. When we send you
emails, we may include a web beacon to allow us to determine the number of people who open our emails. When you
click on a link in an email, we record this individual response to allow us to customize our offerings to you.
Web Beacons cannot be declined when delivered via a regular web page. However, Web Beacons can be refused
when delivered via email. If you do not wish to receive Web Beacons via email, you will need to disable HTML
images or refuse HTML (select Text only) emails via your email software.
6. Linked Sites
For your convenience, our Site mat contain links and/or references to web sites and other services operated by
companies other than Vets First Choice (“Third Party Sites”) that we believe may be of interest to you. Vets First
Choice does not disclose your Personal Information to these Third Party Sites without obtaining your consent. Vets
First Choice does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Sites. While on
these sites, the Third Party Site may collect information about you. Because Vets First Choice does not control the
information policies or practices of these third parties, you should carefully review the privacy policy posted on this
other web site to understand how that Third Party Site collects and uses your Personal Information.
7. Social Media Services.
Through the Site, you can choose to access certain social media websites and services that are owned and/or
controlled by third parties (including, without limitation, Facebook and Twitter) (such websites and services,
collectively, the “Social Media Services”). When you elect to access and use the Social Media Services, you will be
sharing your information (which will include Personal Information if you elect to share such information) with those
Social Media Services. As with other Third Party Sites, the information that you share with the Social Media Services
will be governed by the privacy policies and terms of service of the providers of such Social Media Services and not
by the policies and procedures we describe here. You may also be able to modify your privacy settings with these
Social Media Services to, for example, control what information the Social Media Services disclose to other entities,
including Company. Please remember that the manner in which Social Media Services use, store and disclose your
information is governed by the policies of the applicable Social Media Services provider, and, as a result, we shall not
have any liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of Social Media Services that may be
enabled within and/or otherwise accessible through the Site.
8. Security.
The security and confidentiality of your Personal Information is extremely important to us. We have implemented
technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized
access and improper use. From time to time, we review our security procedures in order to consider appropriate new
technology and methods. Despite Vets First Choice's efforts to protect your Personal Information, there is always
some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your
information over the Internet will be intercepted. In effort to protect your Personal Information, Vets First Choice (by
itself or through its service providers) takes the following steps:
      (a) Requires both a personal username and a password in order for users to access their Personal Information;
      (b) Uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers;
      (c) Utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting Personal Information to our servers. In order
           to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an Internet browser which supports 128-bit
           encryption;
      (d) Monitors the limited number of Vets First Choice employees and Consultants who have potential access to
           Personal Information; and
      (e) Backs-up its systems to protect the integrity of Personal Information.
9. Changes To This Privacy Policy.
Our Site and our business may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for Vets First
Choice to make changes to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any
time and from time to time without prior notice. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will attempt
                                                               4

to notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our Site prior to
the changes becoming effective. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before you provide any
Personal Information. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of our
Service after the effective date of any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with
the terms of such revised Privacy Policy
10.California Online Privacy Protection Act Disclosures.
10.1 Under California Law, California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they
have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of Personal Information and the type of services
provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal
entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, and (b) the
names and addresses of all such third parties. To request the above information, please e-mail us at:
support@vetsfirstchioce.com, or write to us at:
Vets First choice, 110 Exchange Street, Portland, ME 04101 with a reference to California Disclosure Information.
Vets First Choice will respond to such written requests within 30 days following receipt at the e-mail or mailing
address stated above. If we receive your request at a different e-mail or mailing address, we will respond within a
reasonable period of time, but not to exceed 90 days from the date received. Please note that we are only required to
respond to each customer once per calendar year.
10.2 We do not allow third parties to collect Personal Information directly from our users while users participate on the
Site. At this time, we do not respond to web browsers’ “do not track” signals. If we do so in the future, we will describe
how we do so in this Privacy Policy.
11.International Users.
The Site is hosted in the United States and is intended for and directed to users in the United States. If you access
the Site from any region or country with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure,
that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Site, which is governed
by U.S. law, this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your Personal Information to the United
States and you consent to that transfer.
12.Accessing, Changing or Deleting Your Personal Information.
If you want to (a) have your Personal Information deleted from our systems, (b) update the Personal Information that
you have provided to us, or (c) change your preferences with respect to contacts or other activities, you can e-mail us
at support@vetsfirstchoice.com. We try to promptly answer every e-mail, but may not always be able to do so. Keep
in mind, however, that there will be residual i
nformation that will remain within Vets First Choice databases, access logs and other records, which may or may not
contain Personal Information. Vets First Choice reserves the right, from time to time, to re-contact former users of the
Site.
13.Questions, Comments or Concerns.
Should you have any questions, comments or complaints regarding this Agreement or the Site, please contact us via
postal mail at:
Vets First Choice
7 Custom House Street, Suite 5
Portland, ME 04101
Or email us at:
Legal@vetsfirstchoice.com
Copyright ©2015 Direct Vet Marketing, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
                                                             5
